Inkurthi Lakshmi Deepak (1) Featured

Application Software Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Salesforce Development, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Data Loader, Programming, Triggers, SOQL, SOSL, XML



Current Designation: Application Software Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: KOCH Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

[Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application

Development, Salesforce Development, Project Management, Change Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Data Loader, Programming, Triggers, SOQL, SOSL, XML

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Having 5.5+ Yrs of Exp in Salesforce CRM, Lightning Applications.

Around 3+ year of Exp in Salesforce Lightning Development.

Experience on Apex Programming, Visual force Pages.

Experience on REST and SOAP API

Experienced in Email Service and Service based sharing securities in salesforce

Hands on experience in developing apex Triggers, Apex classes and Test classes.

Code optimization with governor limits of Sales force.

Hands on Sandbox Management like Creating new Sandbox and Refresh a Sandbox.

Hands on Partner Relationship Management (PRM Communities) like PRM User setups, PRM Profile, Page Layouts and etc...

Handled Third Party Apps like Albetross, AutoRabit, Aside.io, Sublime Text3,

o MavenMate, Ecilipse, ANT, VS Code

Implementation with Objects, Layouts, Tabs, Validation Rules, Workflows, Process Builder, and Approval process,

Assignment/Sharing Rules OWD Settings.

Created Users, Roles, Profiles and Security Settings based on role hierarchy.

Experience in Reports & Dashboards .

Work Experience

KOCH as Application Software Developer

Mar 2019 to Till Date

I am an individual Salesforce.com Developer involves in Design planning and Requirement Gatherings. More than salesforce.com I also involved in other technologies like AWS, Dell Boomi, SAP modules like BI and Informatica Project #6

Client Project Title Role Duration

KOC H AG & ENE RGY SOLUTIO NS KAES

Application Software Developer. March- 2 019 to till Date

Description:

KOCH AG & ENERGY SOLUTIO NS its affiliates are a global provider of value-added

solutions for the agriculture, turf and ornamental, energy and chemical markets. We are a wholly owned subsidiary of Koch Industries, Inc. In KTC we providing KAES owned products sales and service through salesforce integrated with

AWS & .Net middleware interfaces

Roles & Responsibilities:

- o I nvolved in the sprint planning.
- o Took a part in the project transformation from Opportu nity to Order object upgradation of existing and new functionality.
- o Design patterns to avoid the Test class issues for the old apex classes with new changes.
- o Developing an AP! to connect with AWS.
- o I mplemented Chatter AP! for more reliable communication .
- o I mplementing new custom App builder pages and the components based on the supply demand.
- o Dynamic Component building in lightning experience
- o Code analysis and Conversation impacts discussion with Team.
- o Developer conferences and challenging process debates with in the local development Team (KOCH Principals).
- o Stable Test classes with control of governor Limits.
- o Test Drive Architecture and Business Drive Architecture to improve the standards of the application and the performance with control of change management
- o POC's on LWC to migrate the application from VF page to LWC (for exiting functionality)

Dover as Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2016 to Mar 2019

As a Salesforce.com Implementation in various accepts like Requirement Gathering, Documentation, Problem statements, tool suggestions, Design and Architecture of the requirements. Following the best practices and developed a generalized solution for clients.

Well sound in Programming and Security Management

Project #5

Client Project Title Role Duration

Vehicle Service Group VSG

Salesforce.com Developer. Feb- 2018 to till Date

Vehicle Service Group, LLC man ufactures light and heavy-d uty vehicle lifting and storage lift equipment. It provides pulling equipment, computerized measuring systems, and OE repair data and technician training for body shops, national and regional repair centers, and dealerships; lifts for servicing vehicles for automotive dealerships, general service and specialty repair shops, mass marketers, transit agencies, and government facilities; and resistance welders, plasma cutters, and battery service equipment. The company also offers above ground two-post, four-post, and mid-rise vehicle and motorcycle lifts for small to midsize independent repair shops in North America; light and heavy-d uty Roles & Responsibilities:

- o I nvolved in the requirements gathering and data model design.
- o Partner User Management (Not actual Partner License users).
- o Logic sharing the records based on the Rotary and Chief Brands between same profile users
- o Data Segregation logically between same roles users based on their brands
- o Worked with Dell- Boomi integration issues
- o I mplemented Many-to- Many Relationship between user and Account
- o I mplement the proxy distance calculator custom Apex Development based on latitude and longitude
- o Pre- population of Sate, city and Country based on the ZI P Code Provided by user using USPC integration (Applicable only USA).
- o I nvolved in Salesforce.com Customization and Configuration as per the req uirement
- o Extensively worked on Classic Development and Lightning Components .
- o Created Apex Triggers, Classes and Test Classes as per requirement
- o Created Multistage dynamic Approval Process based on business requirement
- o Worked on Process Builder and Workflow Rules, WF Field updates.
- o Developed Visual force pages based on business reguirement
- o Created Lightning Components for business requirements.
- o Created custom Objects, custom fields, custom settings, custom labels, work flow rules, field update, and email alerts.
- o Custom Lightning Component Development to find nearest distributor in Lead and Work Order
- o Developed various Validation rules as per the business requirement
- o Deployed components from one I nstance to another.
- o Keep tracking of bugs for each delivery, by fixing them in the next release.
- o Prepared the Documentation.

Birlasoft as Software Engineer

Mar 2015 to Jul 2016

Project #2

Client Project Title Role Duration

Environmental Solution Group Case Management Salesforce.com Developer.

J ul- 2016 to Sep- 2 016

Description:

Environmental Solution Group have tracks system as a ticketing tool. Now ESG decided to adopt the salesforce Case management as substitute of tracks system with in line of tracks system.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- o I nvolved in the requirements gathering and data model design.
- o Created Custom fields, workflow rules, workflow alerts, Email Templates, Reports and Dashboards.
- o Multi-step Dynamic Approval Process.

- o Process Builder with invokable apex.
- o Assignment Rules and Escalation rules.
- o Record type with Support Process.
- o Record Sharing settings and Apex Sharing rules for custom sharing to profile users.
- o Design Document and Development Document.
- o Deployment and Code backup.

Project #1

Client Project Title Role Duration

GE

GE Oil & Gas.

Salesforce.com Administrator & Developer. J un- 2015 to J uly- 2016

Description:

GE Oil & Gas was a subsidiary of the American multinational conglomerate corporation General Electric that is now part of Baker Hughes, a GE company. Headquartered in London

United Kingdom, the company supplies equipment for the global oil and gas industry, used in applications across all segments of the oil and gas value chain, including drilling, subsea and offshore, onshore, LNG, distributed gas, pipeline and storage, refinery and petrochemical.

GE Oil & Gas also designs and man ufactures surface and subsea drilling and prod uction systems, equipment for floating prod uction platforms, compressors, turbines, turboexpanders, high pressure reactors, industrial power generation and a broad portfolio of auxiliary equipment. At the 2014 Investor Meeting, it was reported that GE Oil & Gas operate 304 man ufacturing and service shops in the world's main oil and gas extraction and prod uction regions, and provides upgrades to customers' machines.GE Oil & Gas also provide pipeline integrity solutions, sensor-based measurement, inspection, and asset condition monitoring, controls and radiation measurement solutions.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- o I nvolved in Salesforce.com customization as well Configuration as per the req uirement
- o Release management using ANT and Albetross
- o XML Package Preparation .
- o Service Max Configuration and Deployment
- o U pdating or enhancing the Account Module Triggers and apex classes
- o Creating Custom fields and Workflow actions.
- o Profile Settings and Permission set creation
- o Public Groups, Queues and Perm ission Set assignment to users.
- o I mplemented CI for Oil and Gas.
- o Running Complex Deployment and AP! change requests without affecting the Exiting functionality
- o Supporting to dev team in their works whenever they required my help in completing the tasks
- o Code Review and Code Coverage governance for any changes

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Anna University in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Salesforce Devloper DEV401

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
APEX			4 Year(s)
VISUALFORCEPAGE			4 Year(s)
TRIGGERS			4 Year(s)
LIGHTNING		2020	3 Year(s) 1 Month(s)
REST API			1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SOP API			1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SALESFORCE CRM		2020	5 Year(s) 9 Month(s)
VISUALFORCEPAGES	43	2019	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
WORKFLOWS		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SOQL, SOSL		2020	5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Telugu	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Tamil	Beginner			

Projects

Project Title: VSG

Client: Vehicle Service Group Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Feb 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Vehicle Service Group, LLC manufactures light and heavy-duty vehicle lifting and storage lift equipment. It provides pulling equipment, computerized measuring systems, and OE repair data and technician training for body shops, national and regional repair centers, and dealerships; lifts for servicing vehicles for automotive dealerships, general service and specialty repair shops, mass marketers, transit agencies, and government facilities; and resistance welders, plasma cutters, and battery service equipment. The company also offers above ground two-post, four-post, and mid-rise vehicle and motorcycle lifts for small to mid-size independent repair shops in North America; light and heavy-duty

Project Title: Markem-Imaje Client: Markem-Image

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2016 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Markem-Imaje is a trusted world manufacturer of product identification and traceability solutions, offering a full line of reliable and innovative inkjet, thermal transfer, laser, print and apply label systems. Markem-Imaje delivers fully integrated solutions that enable product quality and safety, regulatory and retailer compliance, better product recalls and improved manufacturing processes.

Additionally, Markem-Imaje customers are supported by 6 R&D centers, several equipment repair centers and manufacturing plants strategically located around the globe.

Project Title: TBL Compass

Client: Environmental Solution Group Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2016 - Dec 2017 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Environmental Solution Group is based out of waste management process in USA. ESG Trucks will collect the Garbage from the different parts of the city. Where in ESG have different kinds of Trucks for different categories. To collaborate between partners, distributors and Regional managers. From Dover DIIC suggested the 360-degree view by implementing the TBL Compass as one stop solution with content management system

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time